The HCI community
has developed various techniques
and systems to promote empathy.
A major assumption has been that
letting the user experience
another person's
episode would help the user feel
the same emotion as the other person.
However, we consider that
presenting someone else's
experience in the same way
might not necessarily
evoke the same emotion in the user.
Microaggression is a good example.
Let's see José
and Ashley's conversation.
Alpha, Bravo, Charlie.
Wow, was your dad a pilot?
Ashley feels upset
because she finds a subtle bias
toward women in José’s question,
but José has no idea what is wrong
because he didn't intend any harm to her.
The point is,
even with the same experience,
people may perceive it
differently depending
on their individual background.
In this paper,
we present a novel
concept of fostering
empathy via
generating personalized
analogical experiences,
inducing an individual
to feel emotions similar
to those of the target person.
The idea is that instead of understanding
the experiences of others
from totally different backgrounds
solely through our own perspectives,
we can use our personal experiences
to connect with them emotionally.
As a case study to showcase our concept,
We developed EmoSync,
an LLM-based
agent that generates personalized
analogical microaggression,
so that it facilitates users
to personally resonate
with another person
in a different microaggression.
Let's see the conceptual flow of EmoSync
in José and Ashley's conversation.
José’s EmoSync agent
takes personal information about José,
the microaggression he delivered to Ashley,
and the emotion that Ashley felt.
Then EmoSync generates
an analogical vignette,
which may foster José
to feel similar emotions to Ashley.
With the help of the generated vignette,
José could intuitively understand
why she's upset and empathize with her,
drawing from his own Hispanic background.
We designed and evaluated EmoSync
by 3-phased online user study
with more than 100 participants.
In phase 1,
we make sure the LLM agent understands
and infers an individual's
personalized emotional responses
upon microaggression.
To do so, we collected
a dataset from 41 participants
containing personal information
over four major dimensions.
Based on this dataset,
We designed an LLM prompt
and fine-tuned the types
and amount of personal information.
In phase 2,
we designed the prompt
to generate personalized
analogical microaggression
based on the prompt
developed in phase 1.
The final EmoSync
prompt aims to generate
analogical microaggressions
that elicit emotions
that aligned
with the target emotion,
resonate personally with the user,
and have some analogical connections
to the original microaggression.
Here is an example
generated by EmoSync.
In the pilot experiment
with 10 participants,
we observed
that the analogical microaggression
elicited emotions
closer to the target emotions.
In phase 3,
we explored the efficacy of EmoSync
in multifaceted
empathy factors with 60 participants.
We designed an online survey
to simulate real life communication
that EmoSync assists users
when they struggle to empathize
with a microaggression.
We assessed
how their empathy changed
after seeing a corresponding
analogical microaggression.
As results,
the analogical microaggression
elicit emotions
closer to the target emotions.
After presenting
the analogical microaggression,
participants’ empathy
to original microaggression
improved in multiple dimensions.
The generally perceived EmoSync positively,
highlighting its analogical connections,
personal resonance, and empathic support.
Participants appreciated that EmoSync helps
expanding empathy beyond one's
experience space
and encouraging reflection
and deepening understanding.
They also highlighted
the need for practical
real world applications.
Possible applications
where EmoSync could be directly
adopted and beneficial
would be online chat,
news or social networking platforms.
EmoSync also could be extended
beyond one-on-one communication,
microaggression domain and text modality.
In conclusion,
we propose a novel empathy-enhancing
approach that generates
personalized analogical experiences
to induce individuals
from different backgrounds
to share similar emotions.
A case study on microaggression
with the prototype agent EmoSync,
showcased the multifaceted
empathy-enhancing effects,
highlighting the potential
for our approach to be applied
in various real world
scenarios that require
empathy among diverse people.
For more details,
please refer to our paper. Thank you.